

#### Profile

Engineer specialized in systems analysis with Java language, Microservices in Java, Springboot, Kafka, Oracle, REST standard, using versioning tools with Github and Gitlab, along with continuous delivery and continuous deployment, test tools like Junit and Jmeter, management of core systems and analysis and processing of files in systems, working with Digital transformation within the company,

Using as the main tools of the market for the management and solution of problems.

Management and scheduling of specific processes by Control-M9 (monitoring and schedule tool), data modeling, knowledge methodology Clean architecture, SOLID, Scrum, ITIL and COBIT. Troubleshooting information technology with B2B Sterling Integrator B2B

#### Education

## Software Architecture , Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Minas Gerais, Minas Gerais

July 2018 — November 2020

Case studies and implementation of better software architectures in corporations, application of object-oriented methods, project patterns and market trends in the system architecture Distribuidos by WEB applications and mobile devices

## MBA Oracle Database administrator , IBTA, Sao Paulo area, Brazil January 2016 — June 2018

Studies applied to business models using Oracle tools as a basis, applying the methods taught for the storage and application of information collected and used in entrepreneurship.

#### Employment History

### Java Software Engineer at IBM - Itau Bank, Sao Paulo - Brazil

June 2020 — Present

- Hired to perform digital transformation within a bank account (Banco Itau), Java Web Application Engineer,

with migration of services from high platform (Mainframe) to low platform (Java applications) interconnection of the Bank's area.

- Analysis, understanding and implementation of processes together with the business area and Mainframe analysts for migration of banking processes.
- Creation of Java API Applications from Zero, developed together with the architecture to meet the needs of the business area and for customers
- use of Java 8, Spring Data, Spring Security, JWT token, Oracle Database, DB2 and SQL Server, Microservice Architecture, use of Kafka messaging service to communicate with other microservices using Avro tool

#### **Details**

509 ap 12 Anhembi Street , Santo André - São Paulo, 09291-130, Brasil, +55 11 973-563-451 hueltondihon@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

1985-02-11

Minas Gerais

Nationality

Brazilian

Driving license

Full

#### Links

LinkedIn Git Hub

#### Skills

Teamwork skills

Communication

Respectful

Listening

Fast learning

Java 8

Java 11

**Spring Boot** 

Microservices

Spring Data JPA

**Spring Security** 

Kafka

Avro

**GIT HUB** 

REST API

Docker

- using Jenkins customized for Deploy (CI and CD), using AWS and Openshift for Cloud and Kafka container within AWS for production process.
- Agile methodology, work with international teams, worked with team from Argentina together with people from Brazil.

## Java Software Engineer at Ford Motor Company, São Paulo - Brazil September 2019 — June 2020

- Hired to perform digital transformation within the client, Java web application engineer,

with migration of services from high platform (Mainframe) to low platform (Java applications).

- Understanding of processes together with the business area and Mainframe analysts for process migration.
- Creation of Java API Applications from Zero along with the architecture to meet the needs of the business area and end customer (Ford vehicle dealers)
- use of Java 8, Spring Data, Spring Security, JWT token, Oracle Database, DB2 and SQL Server, Microservice Architecture, use of Kafka messaging service to communicate with other microservices
- using Jenkins for Deploy (CI and CD), using AWS and Pivotal for Cloud container
- Agile methodology, work with international teams, worked with team from Argentina together with people from Brazil.

### Java Developer at RAIA DROGASIL, Sao Paulo

February 2019 — September 2019

Implementation and migration of systems for enterprise application REST services with Springboot and Hibernate JPA persistence, using Sprint and agile amethodology and working with SQUAD team.

# Java Programmer at SPC Brasil at SPC Brasil, São Paulo area, Brazil January 2017 — February 2019

Guidelines for preparing and analyzing process files with company-specific records with precise specifications directed by the Company Projects area. Analysis for spe cific point corrections and updates of BUGs.

Creation of specific reports and creation of scheduled processes for specific clients.

Short shot projects, small changes in the system with involvement and creation

Creation of CRONTAB, java and PL / SQL processes for specific processes in the system.

Development functions in specifics parts is system with designer patterns

## Junior Java Programmer at SPC Brasil, São Paulo area, Brazil

November 2013 — January 2017

Analysis and verification in the company's core system for punctual corrections,

Guidelines for the preparation and analysis of processing files with companyspecific records with precise specifications.

Creation of specific reports and creation of scheduled processes for specific clients.

Kubernetes
PLSQL
SCRUM
JIRA
UML
Oracle DB
SQL Server
Mysql
AWS
OpenShift
Azure
Git Actions
Python
Kotlin
Cobol programming language

#### Languages

Kubarnatas

Portuguese
English
Spanish

#### Hobbies

Play guitar on free time, Study new Technologies, Hangout with my family and friends on the weekends Creation of CRONTAB, Java and PL / SQL processes for specific processes in the system.

#### System Analyst at Imbra Blindados, São Paulo - Brazil

February 2011 — February 2013

Creation of improvements in the company's system and checking of bugs to correct the system, use of monitoring with the client to ensure availability and access, technologies used: Java, JSF, XML, Mysql database, Tom Cat Server

## Certification Exam

**1Z0-051 - Oracle Database: SQL Fundamentals I, Sao Paulo area, Brazil** April 2016 — Present

## International Experiences

#### **International Student, Arlington - Texas**

March 2013 — September 2013

Period of 6 months of permanency in the United States of America, working several activities at the International Students Incorporation University of Texas, in Arlington (ISI UTA).

#### Counselor, Pennsylvania - Philadelphia

June 2013 — July 2013

5 weeks as Counselor in campsites in the United States of America, State of Pennsylvania, working to keep the children safety.

Maranathan Camp and Floddy Camp and Northeast Philadelphia Camp – Pennsylvania – US